Leslie Stephen Photograph Album, 1856-1894
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
- Series VI. Julia and Leslie Stephen, their children, and friends at Talland House, St. Ives, Cornwall, 1880-1894., Leaves: 37-38.
  - Julia Stephen with Virginia and Adrian, 1890s, Anonymous; Silver print 7 x 7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37d)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), seated profile left, with Virginia Woolf (1882-1941) and Adrian Stephen (1883-1948) outside the drawing room window at Talland House.
  - Talland House, c.1882-1894, Anonymous; Silver print 10.3 x 14.8 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37e)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Talland House from tennis ground
    Subject: Side view of the front of Talland House, St Ives, Cornwall, England, from the tennis lawn looking toward the greenhouses.
  - Julia Stephen with Vanessa, Virginia, and Thoby, c.1894, Anonymous; Silver print 7.5 x 7 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Talland House: dining / room window
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) with Vanessa Bell, Virginia Woolf (bending down to a dog), and Thoby Stephen outside the dining room window at Talland House.
  - Talland House, c.1882-1894, Anonymous; Silver print 10.4 x 14.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37g)
    Subject: Front view showing the balconies of Talland House, St Ives, Cornwall, England.
  - St Ives Bay, 1894, Anonymous; Silver print 9.9 x 15.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37h)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Haul of the seine net (1894)
    Subject: Fishing in St Ives Bay, Cornwall, England.
  - Virginia and Adrian Stephen playing cricket, c.1886, Anonymous; Albumen print 11.3 x 13.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37i)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): A.V.S. A.L.S.
    Subject: Virginia Woolf (1882-1941) and Adrian Stephen (1883-1948) playing cricket, St Ives, Cornwall.
    Richardson: Virginia Woolf A2 and Adrian Stephen A2
  - Julia Stephen with Stephen children at lessons, c.1894, Anonymous; Albumen print 7.6 x 10.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): J.T.S., V.S., A.V.S., Julia, A.L.S. (lessons)
    Subject: Thoby Stephen, Vanessa Bell, Virginia Woolf, Julia Duckworth Stephen, and Adrian Stephen at lessons.
    (Cf. 38c)
    Richardson: Stephen children at lessons, c.1894
  - Julia Stephen outside Talland House, c.1894, Anonymous; Silver print 9.7 x 8.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38b)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) outside Talland House among flowers.
  - Julia Stephen and Stephen children, c.1894, Anonymous; Silver print 7.9 x 8.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): V.S. Julia / J.T.S. A.L.S. A.V.S. / (drawing room)
    Subject: Vanessa Bell, Julia Duckworth Stephen, Thoby Stephen, Adrian Stephen, and Virginia Woolf in the front drawing room at Talland House.
  - Julia Stephen and Stella Duckworth, 1894, Anonymous; Silver print 9.7 x 7.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38d)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia & Stella (1894)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) and Stella Duckworth (1869-1897) standing by steps at Talland House.
  - Stephen-Duckworth Group, 1892, Anonymous; Silver print 7.4 x 10.1 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38e)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Horatio Brown Julia, George Gerald / V.S. J.T.S. A.V.S. A.L.S. (Shag)
    Subject: Horatio Brown, Julia Duckworth Stephen, George Duckworth, Gerald Duckworth, Vanessa Bell, Thoby Stephen, Virginia Woolf, Adrian Stephen, and their dog Shag at Talland House.
    Richardson: Stephen-Duckworth Group, 1892
  - Julia Stephen and Stella Duckworth, c.1894, Anonymous; Albumen print 9.5 x 7.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia & Stella (garden walk)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile right, and Stella Duckworth (1869-1897), profile left, sitting on the grass.
    Richardson: Stella Duckworth A5 and Julia Stephen D17
  - Julia Stephen, 1892, Anonymous; Silver print 10.1 x 7.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38g)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): 1892
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) seated reading a book, profile left.
  - Virginia Stephen behind Leslie and Julia Stephen reading, 1893, Anonymous; Silver print 7.9 x 7.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38h)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): 1893
    Subject: Virginia Woolf (1882-1941) behind Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) and Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) reading at Talland House.
    Richardson: Virginia Woolf A13, Leslie Stephen A22, and Julia Stephen D14
  - Julia Stephen, 1892, Anonymous; Silver print 9.9 x 7.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38i)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): (1892) at her desk in the / drawing-room
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile left, sitting at her desk in the drawing room at Talland House.
    (Cf. plate 16)
  - Julia Stephen with Adrian Stephen and Henry James, 1894, Anonymous; Silver print 9.9 x 7.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38j)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Julia, A.L.S., Henry James
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile right, seated on the steps outside Talland House with Adrian Stephen (1883-1948) and Henry James (1843-1916) standing.
  - Julia Stephen, 1894, Anonymous; Silver print 7.0 x 5.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38k)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): 1894
  - Adrian Stephen, Julia Stephen, and Henry James, 1894, Anonymous; Silver print 9.9 x 7.1 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38l)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): A.L.S. Julia / Henry James
    Subject: Henry James (1843-1916) reading on the steps of Talland House with Adrian Stephen (1883-1948) and Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) standing above.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen D15 and Adrian Stephen A13
- Series VII. Julia and Leslie Stephens in Switzerland, 1889., Leaf 39.
  - Julia Stephen, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Silver print 13.5 x 9.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39a)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): (enlarged)
    Subject: Head and shoulders of Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile right, wearing fur-trimmed coat and hat.
  - Julia and Leslie Stephen, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Albumen print 16.8 x 12.0 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39b)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Grindelwald Church-yard.
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) and Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) in a churchyard, Grindelwald, Switzerland.
  - Julia Stephen, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Silver print 16.8 x 11.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39c)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): In the 'Bear' at Grindelwald
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile left, looking out the window indoors at the Bear, Grindelwald, Switzerland.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen D3
  - Leslie and Julia Stephen with Melchior Anderegg, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Albumen print 16.6 x 11.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39d)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): L.S. Julia, Melchior Anderegg / (at Meiringen)
    Subject: Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) and Leslie Stephen(1832-1904) outside with his Alpine guide Melchior Anderegg at Meiringen, Switzerland.
  - Leslie and Julia Stephen, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Albumen print 17.0 x 12.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39e)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): at Grindelwald
    Subject: Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) and Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895), profile left, wearing a fur-trimmed coat and muff outside at Grindelwald, Switzerland.
    Richardson: Julia Stephen D5 and Leslie Stephen A13
  - Madame Loppé with Leslie and Julia Stephen, 1889, Gabriel Loppé; Albumen print 12.0 x 17.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 39f)
    Caption (in Leslie Stephen's autograph): Mme Loppé, L.S., Julia / (at Lauterbrunnen)
    Subject: Madame Loppé, Leslie Stephen (1832-1904) and Julia Duckworth Stephen (1846-1895) indoors at a dining table.
  - Original end-papers from Leslie Stephen's photograph album. (Box 2)
    (The covers are lacking.)
  - Enhanced reproductions from Leslie Stephen's photograph album. (Box 3)
    (Currently on display).